The boys and girls of Sigma Phi. Some will live. Some will die.
Terror Train is a horror, thriller film directed by Roger Spottiswoode.
A masked killer targets six college kids responsible for a prank gone wrong three years earlier and
who are currently throwing a large New Year's Eve costume party aboard a moving train.
Carne, played by Ben Johnson.
Alana, played by Jamie Lee Curtis.
Doc, played by Hart Bochner.
Mitchy, played by Sandee Currie.
Mo, played by Timothy Webber.
Kenny Hampson, played by Derek McKinnon.
Terror Train is a 1980 slasher film directed by Roger Spottiswoode
— in his directorial debut — written by Thomas Y.
Drake, and starring Jamie Lee Curtis, Ben Johnson, Hart Bochner, Timothy
Webber, Anthony Sherwood, Vanity and David Copperfield.
The film follows a group of pre-medical school students holding a New Year's Eve costume party on
a vintage excursion train who are targeted by a killer who dons their costumes.
The concept for the film was based on an idea by executive producer Daniel Grodnik,
who sought to make a movie inspired by Halloween (1978) set on a train.
A full-length script for the film was composed by T.
Drake, and production began within four months.
The film was shot in Montreal between late November and late December 1979,
shortly after Curtis had completed filming for Prom Night (1980).
Terror Train had to have a primarily Canadian cast
and crew to qualify for a tax credit.
An independently produced film, Terror Train was purchased for distribution by the major studio 20th Century Fox, which had yet to
release a slasher film; the studio spent an estimated $5 million on an expansive marketing campaign for the film.
It was released theatrically in the United States on October 3,
1980, grossing $8 million during its theatrical run.
The film's gross disappointed 20th Century Fox, falling
short of their expectations for $40–50 million.
Writer David Grove attributed the movie's box office performance
to an oversaturation of the slasher film market.
Terror Train garnered a mixed reception, with several reviewers
considering it an above-average example of its subgenre.
Critics noted the film's themes of revenge, illusion, and genderbending.
Terror Train became a cult classic, inspiring a remake in 2022,
which was followed by a sequel that same year.
The film explores themes of mask, college, surprise, stalker, revenge.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.